gpf-comics.com 2005-12-14

# GPF: Privacy Statement and Ad Info

Last updated March 26, 2004

Privacy Statement | Our Policy on and Use of "Cookies"  
Advertiser Information | Sonar/DoubleClick "Opt Out"

### Privacy Statement

For [Keenspot](http://www.keenspot.com/)'s privacy statement, please go [here](http://www.keenspot.com/privacy.html).

We here at **GPF** always have and always will respect the privacy of our visitors. In fact, we're probably just as nuts (or more so) about online privacy as you are. **GPF** has never collected and sold private information to anyone for any purpose, and you have our solemn oath that we never will. All forms on this site do exactly what they say they do, and we try our best to spell out all the details before you even get to them.

As a general rule, we here at **GPF** do not collect any information from you other than what is normally supplied by your browser through the course of normal Web browsing activities. This may include (but is not limited to) your IP address, your operating system, your browser name and version, what pages you accessed and how much data you retrieved from our site. This information is aggregated from our server logs and is used only for site maintenance and occasionally for internal marketing research. On rare occasions, aggregate information may be shared with third parties for marketing purposes, but no personally identifiable information will be used. We will hand over our server logs to the proper authorities if required to do so by law, or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with legal process, respond to claims, or to protect the rights, property or safety of our users or the public.

From time to time, we conduct polls of our readers, which are totally anonymous. The questions may contain some demographic information, such as gender, age, general world location, how often you read the strip, etc. All information collected by these surveys is purely voluntary, stored securely on our server, and used solely for making this site as good as it can be. We will never sell or otherwise distribute this information outside our control unless it is aggregated and otherwise cannot be attributed to a single individual.

In the event we may run future contests, we may require you to enter small amounts of personal information, such as your name and e-mail address. We may also attempt to brand your browser with a unique "cookie" ID or store your IP address to help prevent duplicate entries. When we do this, we promise to tell you up front exactly what's going on, and we will never do this without giving you such knowledge first. Any such personal information collected by such a contest will be stored securely on our server, impossible to access from outside sources, and will be promptly destroyed once the contest has been completed. Again, it will never be sold or distributed out of our hands.

### Our Policy on and Use of "Cookies"

For the uninitiated, "cookies" are small snippets of text information stored on your hard drive, saved by your browser. Cookies have a multitude of uses, usually helping maintain state information between pages (such as an online shopping cart system, or perhaps a game). Cookies can and have been used by others for malicious purposes; please rest assured that we here at **GPF** will never use cookies in such a manner.

As a general rule, this site does not use cookies for your basic **GPF** experience (the comic, archives, most fun extras). Our web server may attempt to attach a cookie to your browser on your first visit, but this action is beyond our control and we cannot turn it off. (Subsequently, we will never use this particular cookie for any purpose, either.) Some of our Geeky Games may use cookies to maintain state information, and we may use cookies to help identify your browser in the case of a contest, as mentioned above. Our Archives have a voluntary bookmark feature that also uses a cookie to keep track of where you left off. These cookies will never be set without your knowledge; we will always tell you up front what's going on before it happens, so you can elect not to participate in or use these features if you feel uncomfortable. In most cases, we will also provide some method of destroying the cookie and thus "unbranding" your browser if the feature is no longer needed or desired.

We cannot be held responsible for any use of cookies, legitimate or otherwise, made by our advertisers.

### Advertiser Information

To help keep our site free and open to everyone, we have elected to display banner advertising on most of our pages. In return for displaying their ads, we receive monetary compensation. Not much, but it's more than nothing. We have little to no control over the content of these banner ads, where they may lead, and the contents of the sites they may lead to. As such, we cannot be held responsible for any offensive or malicious content that may appear on these ads or their feature sites. If you do find any offensive, malicious, or illegal material in such a banner ad, please check this question in our FAQ to see how to report this ad so it can be banned.

There is always the possibility that banner ads may include JavaScript, Java, Flash, may attempt to set a "cookie," or even attempt to install "spyware" or other software without your permission. All such code is completely out of our control, and we cannot be held responsible for any such code that may affect your browser in any fashion. (Some banner ads have been known to crash browsers, much to our dismay.) We also cannot be held responsible if one of these advertisers attempts to collect your personal information through a banner ad; we personally find such an act to be unscrupulous and devious, but there's little we can do about it, if it occurs. If you believe your personal information is being spirited away by such an ad, please check this question in our FAQ to see how to report this ad so it can be banned.

There have been, in some cases, advertisers who have displayed ads on our site that represent or promote ideas, products, or services that are neither endorsed nor supported by the **GPF** team. In fact, we have even noticed an ad or two that directly contradicts our personal views and beliefs. In no way, shape, or form should it be mistaken that display of any banner ad on the **GPF** site implies our support or endorsement of the products, services, or ideas represented by any ad. We cannot vouch for any advertiser, aside from the fact that they pay us to display their ads. If you choose to use an advertiser's product or service based upon seeing their ad here on **GPF** , you do so at your own risk.

Each advertiser usually maintains their own privacy policies and procedures. For your convenience, we've included links to their privacy pages here:

[Keenspot](http://www.keenspot.com/) is also now managing their own advertising, and is taking direct advertising contracts. If you are interested in advertising on this or other Keenspot sites, feel free to explore the [Keenspot Media Kit](http://www.keenspot.com/mediakit/) or [contact Keenspot](mailto:keenspot@keenspot.com?subject=Advertising%20Info) for more information.

In addition, Keenspot has now launched [Keenspot PREMIUM](http://www.keenspot.org/premium/), a subscription-based service that allows you to surf all of Keenspot ad-free for a small fee. In addition, subscriptions allow you to gain access to exclusive content and free original art or comics. We here at **GPF** heartily endorse Keenspot PREMIUM as a kewl, nifty way to enjoy our comic without pop-up banners and other annoying distractions. Please see the Keenspot PREMIUM site at the link above for more details.

### Sonar/DoubleClick "Opt Out"

Many of you may already be aware that Sonar and its parent company, [DoubleClick](http://www.doubleclick.net/), have been the center of some debate concerning online privacy. To summarize, DoubleClick merged with another company which specialized in maintaining large marketing databases containing the names, addresses, and other contact information for many, many consumers. DoubleClick announced their plans to connect their current Web surfing tracking database with this marketing database, a move which, in short, would enable them to connect an individual's Web surfing habits with their personal contact information. Up until this announcement, Web surfing has largely been an anonymous activity. Many privacy advocates cried foul over the announcement and, under a great deal of pressure from the Internet community, DoubleClick backed down and promised not to pursue this activity... _for the time being._

Under this pressure, DoubleClick also created an "opt out" system, which effectively disables their ability to track a Web surfer's movements. Their advertising system "brands" visitors through advertising code with an individual and unique "cookie," which can then be followed across any site displaying DoubleClick ads, and thus feeding their browsing habits to DoubleClick. The "opt out" system disables this cookie, crippling the tracking system and removing any personalization involved.

We here at **GPF** personally feel that DoubleClick's actions in attempting to link personal contact information with Web surfing habits is dubious at best, sinister at worst. We feel that your right to freedom is important, and that your privacy should be cherished and protected. As such, we would like to offer you the opportunity to join us in "opting out" of DoubleClick's tracking system and returning anonymity to your Web surfing enjoyment. To activate the "opt out," simply follow the link below and follow the page's instructions.

 **> >> [Click here to "opt out" of DoubleClick's tracking system.](http://www.doubleclick.com/us/about_doubleclick/privacy/ad-cookie/) <<<**
